<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Novel CS</title>
    <link>https://example.org/docs/cloud-computing-and-infrastructure/aws/load-balancer/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Novel CS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://example.org/docs/cloud-computing-and-infrastructure/aws/load-balancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.org/docs/cloud-computing-and-infrastructure/aws/load-balancer/application-load-balancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/docs/cloud-computing-and-infrastructure/aws/load-balancer/application-load-balancer/</guid>
      <description>How Application Load Balancers work # Clients make requests to your application. The listeners in your load balancer receive requests matching the protocol and port that you configure. The receiving listener evaluates the incoming request against the rules you specify, and if applicable, routes the request to the appropriate target group. You can use an HTTPS listener to offload the work of TLS encryption and decryption to your load balancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.org/docs/cloud-computing-and-infrastructure/aws/load-balancer/port/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/docs/cloud-computing-and-infrastructure/aws/load-balancer/port/</guid>
      <description>QUESTION # There are four ports can be configured in load-balancer related settings.
The port of the listener The port of the target group The port of the target group health checking The port of the instance in the target group So what is the meaning of the port of the target group?
ANSWER # The port of the listener is used to receive all the incoming requests and data sent to the load-balancer through that port.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.org/docs/cloud-computing-and-infrastructure/aws/load-balancer/sticky-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/docs/cloud-computing-and-infrastructure/aws/load-balancer/sticky-session/</guid>
      <description>What is sticky session? # By default, an Application Load Balancer routes each request independently to a registered target based on the chosen load-balancing algorithm. However, you can use the sticky session feature (also known as session affinity) to enable the load balancer to bind a user&amp;rsquo;s session to a specific target.
This ensures that all requests from the user during the session are sent to the same target. This feature is useful for servers that maintain state information in order to provide a continuous experience to clients.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
