<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Novel CS</title>
    <link>https://example.org/docs/aws/vpc/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Novel CS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://example.org/docs/aws/vpc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.org/docs/aws/vpc/eni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/docs/aws/vpc/eni/</guid>
      <description>Elastic Network Interface # To understand how AWS achieves the AWSVPC network mode for containers, which allows them to have their own network settings regardless of the instance&amp;rsquo;s network configuration, we need to look into the underlying technology and AWS&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure capabilities:
Elastic Network Interface (ENI): In AWSVPC mode, each ECS task is assigned its own Elastic Network Interface (ENI). An ENI is a virtual network interface that you can attach to an instance in a VPC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.org/docs/aws/vpc/gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/docs/aws/vpc/gateway/</guid>
      <description>NAT Gateway # Internet Gateway # An Internet Gateway is used to allow resources in your network to access the internet, and to allow the internet to connect to those resources. It serves as a route for internet traffic from and to a network. In a cloud environment like AWS (Amazon Web Services), an Internet Gateway is attached to a VPC (Virtual Private Cloud) to enable communication between instances in the VPC and the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.org/docs/aws/vpc/route-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/docs/aws/vpc/route-table/</guid>
      <description>Subnet -&amp;gt; Route Table # in AWS, each subnet can only be associated with one route table at a time. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it works:
Single Route Table per Subnet: If you need different routing rules for different parts of your network, you need to create multiple subnets and associate each with a different route table. Multiple Subnets per Route Table: Conversely, a single route table can be associated with multiple subnets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.org/docs/aws/vpc/vpc-endpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/docs/aws/vpc/vpc-endpoint/</guid>
      <description>VPC Endpoints # There are three types of VPC endpoints – Interface endpoints, Gateway Load Balancer endpoints, and Gateway endpoints. Interface endpoints and Gateway Load Balancer endpoints are powered by AWS PrivateLink, and use an Elastic Network Interface (ENI) as an entry point for traffic destined to the service. Interface endpoints are typically accessed using the public or private DNS name associated with the service, while Gateway endpoints and Gateway Load Balancer endpoints serve as a target for a route in your route table for traffic destined for the service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.org/docs/aws/vpc/vpc-peering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/docs/aws/vpc/vpc-peering/</guid>
      <description>Configuration # Have to add routes to both two subnets&amp;rsquo; route table. Route table Destination Target VPC A VPC A CIDR Local VPC B CIDR pcx-11112222 VPC B VPC B CIDR Local VPC A CIDR pcx-11112222 No unidirection access if only one route is added to one subnet&amp;rsquo;s route table. Route table Destination Target VPC A VPC A CIDR Local VPC B CIDR pcx-11112222 VPC B VPC B CIDR Local OR</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
